<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://sioc-project.org"  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
 <title>sioc-project.org</title>
 <link>http://sioc-project.org</link>
 <description>

The SIOC initiative (Semantically-Interlinked Online Communities) aims to enable the integration of online community information.  SIOC provides a Semantic Web ontology for representing rich data from the Social Web in RDF.  It has recently achieved significant adoption through its usage in a variety of commercial and open-source software applications, and is commonly used in conjunction with the FOAF vocabulary for expressing personal profile and social networking information.  By becoming a standard way for expressing user-generated content from such sites, SIOC enables new kinds of usage scenarios for online community site data, and allows innovative semantic applications to be built on top of the existing Social Web.  The SIOC ontology was recently published as a W3C Member Submission, which was submitted by 16 organisations.</description>
 <language>en</language>
<item>
 <title>DERI “SIOC” Research Wins Seven-Year Influential Paper Award</title>
 <link>http://sioc-project.org/node/343</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;A paper on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://sioc-project.org&quot;&gt;SIOC&lt;/a&gt; framework from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.deri.ie&quot;&gt;Digital Enterprise Research Institute&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nuigalway.ie&quot;&gt;NUI Galway&lt;/a&gt;, funded by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sfi.ie&quot;&gt;Science Foundation Ireland&lt;/a&gt;, has just been announced as the winner of the seven-year influential paper award from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://eswc-conferences.org&quot;&gt;Extended Semantic Web Conference&lt;/a&gt; (ESWC), an annual conference held in Europe that focuses on next-generation web technologies.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper, entitled “&lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/KQ2iK4&quot;&gt;Towards Semantically-Interlinked Online Communities&lt;/a&gt;”, was published in 2005, and has been cited over 170 times. The paper received glowing praise from the award reviewers in terms of impact, community, tool availability and sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SIOC provides methods for interconnecting Social Web platforms such as forums, blogs and microblogs to each other. It consists of the SIOC ontology, an open-standard machine readable format for expressing the structure of Internet discussion methods, of SIOC metadata producers for a number of popular social platforms and content management systems, and of storage and browsing/searching systems for leveraging this SIOC data. SIOC has since been deployed in hundreds of platforms on thousands of websites including Yahoo! SearchMonkey, the Newsweek website, and various US Government agencies powered by Drupal 7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper authors are John Breslin, social software team leader at DERI and lecturer in Engineering and Informatics at NUI Galway; Andreas Harth, former researcher at DERI and now a postdoctoral researcher at the Karlsruhe Institute of Technology; Uldis Bojars, a PhD graduate from DERI, NUI Galway and now a researcher at the National Library of Latvia, and Stefan Decker, director of DERI, NUI Galway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Judging the competition were Asunción Gómez-Pérez, Artificial Intelligence (AI) director from UPM Madrid, Spain; James Hendler, an AI researcher at Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, USA, and one of the originators of the Semantic Web; and Frank van Harmelen, Professor of Knowledge Representation and Reasoning at the VU University Amsterdam, The Netherlands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper can be downloaded at: &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/KQ2iK4&quot;&gt;http://bit.ly/KQ2iK4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://sioc-project.org/node/343#comments</comments>
 <category domain="http://sioc-project.org/taxonomy/term/10">General</category>
 <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2012 11:57:21 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Cloud</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">343 at http://sioc-project.org</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Tales From the SIOC-O-Sphere #10</title>
 <link>http://sioc-project.org/node/342</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://sioc-project.org/files/siocapps_medium.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://sioc-project.org/&quot;&gt;SIOC&lt;/a&gt; is a Social Semantic Web project that originated at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.deri.ie/&quot;&gt;DERI&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nuigalway.ie&quot;&gt;NUI Galway&lt;/a&gt; (funded by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sfi.ie/&quot;&gt;SFI&lt;/a&gt;) and which aims to interlink online communities with semantic technologies. You can read more about SIOC on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SIOC&quot;&gt;Wikipedia page for SIOC&lt;/a&gt; or in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.johnbreslin.org/files/publications/20080513_is__2008.pdf&quot;&gt;this paper&lt;/a&gt;. But in brief, SIOC provides a set of terms that describe the main concepts in social websites: posts, user accounts, thread structures, reply counts, blogs and microblogs, forums, etc. It can be used for interoperability between social websites, for augmenting search results, for data exchange, for enhanced feed readers, and more. It&#039;s also one of the metadata formats used in the forthcoming Drupal 7 content management system, and has been deployed on hundreds of websites including Newsweek.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of our dissemination activities, I&#039;ve tried to regularly summarise recent developments in the project so as to give an overview of what&#039;s going on and also to help in connecting interested parties. It&#039;s been much too long (over a year) since &lt;a href=&quot;http://sioc-project.org/node/336&quot;&gt;my last report&lt;/a&gt;, so this will be a long one! In reverse chronological order, here&#039;s a list of recent applications and websites that are using SIOC:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;SMOB Version 2.&lt;/b&gt; As you may have &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.ycombinator.net/item?id=1453685&quot;&gt;read on Y Combinator Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; yesterday, a re-architected and re-coded version of &lt;a href=&quot;http://smob.me/&quot;&gt;SMOB&lt;/a&gt; (Semantic Microblogging) has been &lt;a href=&quot;http://apassant.net/blog/2010/01/22/smob-v20&quot;&gt;created by Alex Passant&lt;/a&gt;. As with our original SMOB design, a user&#039;s SMOB site stores and shares tweets and user information using SIOC and FOAF, but the new version also exposes data via RDFa and additional vocabularies (including the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.onlinepresenceontology&quot;&gt;Online Presence Ontology&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://moat-project.org/&quot;&gt;MOAT&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://commontag.org/&quot;&gt;Common Tag&lt;/a&gt;). The new SMOB suggests relevant URIs from DBpedia and Sindice when #hashtags are entered, and has moved from a client-server model to a set of distributed hubs. &lt;i&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/terraces&quot;&gt;@terraces&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;on-the-wave.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://on-the-wave.googlecode.com/&quot;&gt;This script&lt;/a&gt; creates an enhanced browsing experience (that is SIOC-enabled) for the popular &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PTT_Bulletin_Board_System&quot;&gt;PTT bulletin board system&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:kennyluck@csail.mit.edu&quot;&gt;kennyluck@csail.mit.edu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Newsweek.com.&lt;/b&gt; American news magazine &lt;a href=&quot;http://newsweek.com/&quot;&gt;Newsweek&lt;/a&gt; are now publishing RDFa on their main site, including DC, CommonTag, FOAF and SIOC. &lt;i&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/markcatalano&quot;&gt;@markcatalano&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Linked Data from Picasa.&lt;/b&gt; OpenLink Software&#039;s URI Burner can now provide Linked Data views of Google Picasa photo albums. See an example &lt;a href=&quot;http://linkeddata.uriburner.com/about/html/http://linkeddata.uriburner.com/about/id/entity/http/picasaweb.google.com/data/feed/api/user/swaminarayangurukul/albumid/5455217237148353985&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/kidehen&quot;&gt;@kidehen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Facebook Open Graph Protocol.&lt;/b&gt; Facebook recently announced its &lt;a href=&quot;http://opengraphprotocol.org/&quot;&gt;Open Graph Protocol&lt;/a&gt; (OGP), which allows any web page to become a rich object in their social graph. While OGP defines its own set of classes and properties, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://opengraphprotocol.org/schema/&quot;&gt;RDF schema&lt;/a&gt; contains direct mappings to existing concepts in FOAF, DBpedia and BIBO, and indirect mappings to concepts in Geo, vCard, SIOC and GoodRelations. OpenLink also have a data dictionary meshup of some OGP and SIOC terms (&lt;a href=&quot;http://lod.openlinksw.com/describe/?url=http://opengraphprotocol.org/schema/Blog&quot;&gt;ogp:Blog is mapped to sioct:Weblog&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;i&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/daveman692&quot;&gt;@daveman692&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Linked Data from Slideshare.&lt;/b&gt; A service to produce Linked Data from the popular Slideshare presentation sharing service has been created, and is available &lt;a href=&quot;http://linkeddata.few.vu.nl/slideshare/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Data is represented in SIOC and DC. &lt;i&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/pgroth&quot;&gt;@pgroth&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Fanhubz.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://fanhu.bz/&quot;&gt;FanHubz&lt;/a&gt; supports community building and discovery around BBC content items such as TV shows and radio programmes. It &lt;a href=&quot;http://fanhu.bz/schema#&quot;&gt;reuses the sioct:MicroblogPost term&lt;/a&gt; and also has some interesting &lt;a href=&quot;http://fanhu.bz/annotations#&quot;&gt;additional annotation terms&lt;/a&gt; for in-show tweets (e.g. twitterSubtitles). &lt;i&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/ldodds&quot;&gt;@ldodds&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;RDFa-enhanced FusionForge.&lt;/b&gt; An &lt;a href=&quot;http://forge.projet-coclico.org/scm/loggerhead/coclico/fusionforge-5.0+coclico/patches/rdfa/files&quot;&gt;RDFa-enhanced version of FusionForge&lt;/a&gt;, a software project management and collaboration system, has been created that generates metadata about projects, users and groups using SIOC, DOAP and FOAF. You can look at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://forge.projet-coclico.org/plugins/mediawiki/wiki/wp2/index.php/Forge_Ontology_Proposal&quot;&gt;Forge ontology proposal&lt;/a&gt;, and also view a &lt;a href=&quot;http://forge.projet-coclico.org/&quot;&gt;demo site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/olberger&quot;&gt;@olberger&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Falconer.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://iws.seu.edu.cn/services/Falconer/&quot;&gt;Falconer&lt;/a&gt; is a Semantic Web search engine application enhanced with SIOC. It allows newly-created Social Web content to be represented in SIOC, but it also allows this content to be annotated with any semantic statements available from &lt;a href=&quot;http://iws.seu.edu.cn/services/falcons&quot;&gt;Falcons&lt;/a&gt;, and all of this data can then be indexed by the search engine to form an ecosystem of semantic data. &lt;i&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:wu@seu.edu.cn&quot;&gt;wu@seu.edu.cn&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Django to RDF.&lt;/b&gt; A script is available &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/rdfpyintra&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to turn Django data into SIOC RDF and JSON. View the full repository of related scripts on &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/valtech/nosql&quot;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/niklasl&quot;&gt;@niklasl&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;SIOC Actions Module.&lt;/b&gt; A new SIOC module has been created to describe &lt;a href=&quot;http://rdfs.org/sioc/actions&quot;&gt;actions&lt;/a&gt;, with potential applications ranging from modelling actions in a developer community to tracing interactions in large-scale wikis. There is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://champin.net/wsgi/siocat/&quot;&gt;SIOC Actions translator site&lt;/a&gt; for converting Activity Streams, Wikipedia interactions and Subversion actions into RDF. &lt;i&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/pchampin&quot;&gt;@pchampin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;SIOC Quotes Module.&lt;/b&gt; Another SIOC module has been developed for representing &lt;a href=&quot;http://rdfs.org/sioc/quotes&quot;&gt;quotes&lt;/a&gt; in e-mail conversations and other social media content. You can view a &lt;a href=&quot;http://slideshare.net/terraces/a-semantic-framework-for-modelling-quotes-in-email-conversations&quot;&gt;presentation&lt;/a&gt; on this topic. &lt;i&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/terraces&quot;&gt;@terraces&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Siocwave.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/siocwave/&quot;&gt;Siocwave&lt;/a&gt; is a desktop tool for viewing and exploring SIOC data, and is based on Python, RDFLib and wxWidgets. &lt;i&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:vfaronov@gmail.com&quot;&gt;vfaronov@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;RDFa in Drupal 7.&lt;/b&gt; Following the &lt;a href=&quot;http://drupal.org/node/443824&quot;&gt;Drupal RDF code sprint&lt;/a&gt; in DERI last year, RDFa support (FOAF, SIOC, SKOS, DC) in Drupal core was &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/dries/status/4997311434&quot;&gt;committed to version 7 in October&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://drupal.org/project/issues/search/drupal?status[]=Open&amp;amp;issue_tags=RDF&amp;amp;version[]=7.x&quot;&gt;work has been apace on refining this module&lt;/a&gt;. Drupal 7 is currently on its fifth alpha version, and a full release candidate is expected later this summer. Find out more about the RDFa in Drupal initiative at &lt;a href=&quot;http://semantic-drupal.com/&quot;&gt;semantic-drupal.com&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/scorlosquet&quot;&gt;@scorlosquet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Omeka Linked Data Plugin (Forthcoming).&lt;/b&gt; A plugin to produce Linked Data from the Omeka web publishing platform is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.patrickgmj.net/node/177&quot;&gt;in progress&lt;/a&gt; that will generate data using SIOC, FOAF, DOAP and other formats. &lt;i&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/patrickgmj&quot;&gt;@patrickgmj&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Boeing inSite.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2009/Talks/Boeing-tpac09.pdf&quot;&gt;inSite&lt;/a&gt; is an &lt;a href=&quot;https://insite.web.boeing.com/&quot;&gt;internal&lt;/a&gt; social media platform for Boeing employees that provides SIOC and FOAF data services as part of its architecture. &lt;i&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/adamboyet&quot;&gt;@adamboyet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Virtuoso Sponger.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://virtuoso.openlinksw.com/dataspace/dav/wiki/Main/VirtSponger&quot;&gt;Virtuoso Sponger&lt;/a&gt; is a middleware component of Virtuoso that generates RDF Linked Data from a variety of data sources (working as an &quot;RDFizer&quot;). It supports SIOC as an input format, and also uses SIOC as its data space &quot;glue&quot; ontology (view the &lt;a href=&quot;http://slidesix.com/view/VirtuosoSponger1&quot;&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;i&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/kidehen&quot;&gt;@kidehen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;SuRF.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/surfrdf/&quot;&gt;SuRF&lt;/a&gt; is a Python library for working with RDF data in an object-oriented way, with SIOC being one of the default namespaces. &lt;i&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:basca@ifi.uzh.ch&quot;&gt;basca@ifi.uzh.ch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Triplify phpBB 3.&lt;/b&gt; A &lt;a href=&quot;http://triplify.org/Configuration/phpBB?v=qph&quot;&gt;Triplify configuration file for phpBB 3&lt;/a&gt; has been created that allows RDF data (including SIOC) to be generated from this popular bulletin board system. Various other &lt;a href=&quot;http://triplify.org/Documentation&quot;&gt;Triplify configurations&lt;/a&gt; are also available. &lt;i&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:auer@informatik.uni-leipzig.de&quot;&gt;auer@informatik.uni-leipzig.de&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;SiocLog.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/tuukka/sioclog&quot;&gt;SiocLog&lt;/a&gt; is an IRC logging application that provides discussion channels and chat user profiles as Linked Data, using SIOC and FOAF respectively. You can see a &lt;a href=&quot;http://irc.sioc-project.org/&quot;&gt;deployment&lt;/a&gt; and view our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slideshare.net/Cloud/sioclog-providing-irc-discussion-logs-as-linked-data&quot;&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/tuukkah&quot;&gt;@tuukkah&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;myExperiment Ontology.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.myexperiment.org/&quot;&gt;myExperiment&lt;/a&gt; is a collaborative environment where scientists can publish their workflows and experiment plans, share them with groups and find those of others. In their model, myExperiment reuses ontologies like DC, FOAF, SIOC, CC and OAI-ORE. &lt;i&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:drn@ecs.soton.ac.uk&quot;&gt;drn@ecs.soton.ac.uk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;aTag.&lt;/b&gt; The &lt;a href=&quot;http://hcls.deri.org/atag/generator/&quot;&gt;aTag&lt;/a&gt; generator produces snippets of HTML enriched with SIOC RDFa and DBpedia-linked tags about highlighted items of interest on any web page, but aiming at the biomedical domain. &lt;i&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/matthiassamwald&quot;&gt;@matthiassamwald&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;ELGG SID Module.&lt;/b&gt; A Semantically-Interlinked Data (SID) module for the ELGG educational social network system &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scribd.com/doc/19413487/Weaving-Social-ELearning-Platforms-Into-the-Web-of-Linked-Data&quot;&gt;has been described&lt;/a&gt; that allows UGC and tags from ELGG platforms to become part of the Linked Data cloud. &lt;i&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/selvers&quot;&gt;@selvers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Liferay Linked Data Module.&lt;/b&gt; The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.liferay.com/web/bryan.cheung/blog/-/blogs/liferay-linked-data-module&quot;&gt;Linked Data module for Liferay&lt;/a&gt;, an enterprise portal solution, supports mapping of data to the SIOC, MOAT and FOAF vocabularies. &lt;i&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;twitter.com/bryan_&quot;&gt;@bryan_&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;ourSpaces.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ourspaces.net/&quot;&gt;ourSpaces&lt;/a&gt; is a VRE enabling online collaboration between researchers from various disciplines. It combines FOAF and SIOC with data provenance ontologies for sharing digital artefacts. &lt;i&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:r.reid@abdn.ac.uk&quot;&gt;r.reid@abdn.ac.uk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Good Relations and SIOC.&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://ebusiness-unibw.org/pipermail/goodrelations/2009-June/000057.html&quot;&gt;This post&lt;/a&gt; describes nicely how the Good Relations vocabulary for e-commerce can be combined with SIOC, e.g. to link a gr:Offering (either being offered or sought by a gr:BusinessEntity) to a natural-language discussion about that thing in a sioc:Post. &lt;i&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:sdmonroe@gmail.com&quot;&gt;sdmonroe@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Debian BTS to RDF.&lt;/b&gt; Discussions from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www-public.it-sudparis.eu/~dang_qua/pmwiki/pmwiki.php?n=Blog.DebianSocialNetwork&quot;&gt;Debian bug-tracking system (BTS) can be converted to SIOC and RDF&lt;/a&gt; and browsed or visualised in interesting ways, e.g. who replied to whom. &lt;i&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:quang_vu.dang@it-sudparis.eu&quot;&gt;quang_vu.dang@it-sudparis.eu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;RDFex.&lt;/b&gt; For those wishing to reuse parts of popular vocabularies in their own Semantic Web vocabularies, &lt;a href=&quot;http://rdfex.org/&quot;&gt;RDFex&lt;/a&gt; is a mechanism for importing snippets from other namespaces without having to copy and paste them. RDFex can be used as a proxy for various ontologies including DC, FOAF and SIOC. &lt;i&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:holger@knublauch.com&quot;&gt;holger@knublauch.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;IRC Logger with RDFa and SIOC.&lt;/b&gt; A fork of Dave Beckett&#039;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dajobe.org/software/logger/&quot;&gt;IRC Logger&lt;/a&gt; has been created &lt;a href=&quot;http://goddamn.co.uk/viewvc/logger-sioc-rdfa/&quot;&gt;to include support for RDFa and SIOC&lt;/a&gt; by Toby Inkster. &lt;i&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:mail@tobyinkster.co.uk&quot;&gt;mail@tobyinkster.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;mbox2rdf.&lt;/b&gt; A &lt;a href=&quot;http://goddamn.co.uk/viewvc/misc/mbox2rdf/&quot;&gt;mbox2rdf&lt;/a&gt; script has been created that converts a mailing list in an mbox file to RDF (RSS, SIOC and DC). &lt;i&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:mail@tobyinkster.co.uk&quot;&gt;mail@tobyinkster.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Chisimba SIOC Export Module.&lt;/b&gt; A &lt;a href=&quot;http://cvs2.uwc.ac.za/trac/chisimba/browser/modules/trunk/siocexport&quot;&gt;SIOC Export module&lt;/a&gt; for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://avoir.uwc.ac.za/&quot;&gt;Chisimba&lt;/a&gt; CMS/LMS platform has been created, which allows various Chisimba modules (CMS, forum, blog, Jabberblog, Twitterizer) to &lt;a href=&quot;http://tweetgator.peeps.co.za/index.php?module=twitterizer&amp;amp;action=sioc&amp;amp;sioc_type=site&quot;&gt;export SIOC data&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;i&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/paulscott56&quot;&gt;@paulscott56&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;vBulletin SIOC Exporter.&lt;/b&gt; Omitted from the last report, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.sioc-project.org/index.php/VBSIOC&quot;&gt;vBulletin SIOC plugin&lt;/a&gt; generates SIOC and FOAF data from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vbulletin.com/&quot;&gt;vBulletin&lt;/a&gt; discussion forums. It includes a plugin that allows users to opt to export the SHA1 of their e-mail address (and other inverse functional properties) and their network of friends via vBulletin&#039;s user control panel. &lt;i&gt;Contact &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/johnbreslin&quot;&gt;@johnbreslin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Discuss SIOC on Google Wave&lt;/b&gt;. You can now chat about SIOC on our &lt;a href=&quot;https://wave.google.com/wave/waveref/googlewave.com/w+08dUYQNiA&quot;&gt;Google Wave&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://sioc-project.org/node/342#comments</comments>
 <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2010 19:05:00 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Cloud</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">342 at http://sioc-project.org</guid>
</item>
<item>
 <title>Major change to a SIOC term: User is now called UserAccount</title>
 <link>http://sioc-project.org/node/341</link>
 <description>&lt;p&gt;As per recent &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/sioc-dev/browse_frm/thread/7f3a19f4645abbb1&quot;&gt;discussions on the SIOC developers mailing list&lt;/a&gt; and requests from many parties requesting clarification of the term sioc:User (which has oft been confused with foaf:Person), we are happy to announce that the new term &lt;b&gt;sioc:UserAccount&lt;/b&gt; has been added to the ontology in replacement of the now-deprecated sioc:User term (in revision 1.35 of the SIOC ontology).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://rdfs.org/sioc/spec&quot;&gt;SIOC specification&lt;/a&gt; has been updated accordingly, and knock-on effects to SIOC modules have been corrected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;We would ask all application maintainers to update your code to reflect this change, i.e., replace User with the new term UserAccount.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are attaching updates to the various figures showing the connections internally between SIOC terms, and also between SIOC, &lt;a class=&quot;zem_slink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.foaf-project.org/&quot; title=&quot;FOAF&quot; rel=&quot;homepage&quot;&gt;FOAF&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&quot;zem_slink&quot; href=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2004/02/skos/&quot; title=&quot;SKOS&quot; rel=&quot;homepage&quot;&gt;SKOS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please discuss this change &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/sioc-dev/browse_frm/thread/ce321a18b39087b&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://sioc-project.org/files/main_classes_properties_useraccount_change.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;The main classes and properties in SIOC, reflecting the UserAccount change.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://sioc-project.org/files/sioc_foaf_skos_useraccount_change.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;The relationships between SIOC, FOAF and SKOS, reflecting the UserAccount change.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://sioc-project.org/files/dataportability_useraccount_change.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;An example of content created by a person across multiple sites, linked to a foaf:Person via multiple sioc:UserAccounts.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 10px; height: 15px;&quot; class=&quot;zemanta-pixie&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zemanta-pixie-a&quot; href=&quot;http://reblog.zemanta.com/zemified/8bf389a4-5598-44b1-9779-9f0c4546a0bd/&quot; title=&quot;Reblog this post [with Zemanta]&quot;&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;border: medium none; float: right;&quot; class=&quot;zemanta-pixie-img&quot; src=&quot;http://img.zemanta.com/reblog_e.png?x-id=8bf389a4-5598-44b1-9779-9f0c4546a0bd&quot; alt=&quot;Reblog this post [with Zemanta]&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;zem-script more-related pretty-attribution&quot;&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;http://static.zemanta.com/readside/loader.js&quot; defer=&quot;defer&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
 <comments>http://sioc-project.org/node/341#comments</comments>
 <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2010 15:24:53 +0000</pubDate>
 <dc:creator>Cloud</dc:creator>
 <guid isPermaLink="false">341 at http://sioc-project.org</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
